Okay, so we've got a few different types of metrics we're interested in.
我们得到了一些我们感兴趣的不同类型的指标
There's the sanity checking metrics and then there's the evaluation metrics,
有完整性检查指标和评价指标
which breaks down into these overall business metrics and the more detailed
这些又分为总体业务指标和更详细的指标
metrics, but for all of these, how do we actually go about making a definition?
但我们如何对所有这些指标定义呢？
>> Well, there's really a bunch of different steps.
这个需要很多不同的步骤
The first is you want to come up with a high level concept for a metric.
首先要为一个指标想出一个高级概念
This is going to be your one sentence summary that everyone is going to be
也就是一句话总结 通过这句话大家能够理解这个指标
able to understand, something like "active users" or
如“活跃用户”或
"click-through probability".
“点击概率”
Everyone sort of understands that.
每个人都能够理解
But then, from there,
然后
the second step is to really figure out all of the nitty gritty details.
第二步是确定各个细节
These are going to be things like, okay, you want to measure active users.
如你想测定活跃用户
How do you define what active is?
你如何定义活跃？
Is it a seven day active, is it a 28 day active?
7 天算活跃 还是 28 天才算活跃？
Which events count towards activity?
哪些事件可以算为活跃？
Right? An automatic notification may not count
对不对？自动通知不能将其算为
towards it being an active user.
活跃用户
The third step is that you are taking all of these individual data
第三步是你进行单独数据测量之后
measurements, and now you need to summarize them into a single metric.
你需要将它们总结为一个指标
Maybe, maybe this is something like a sum or a count, could be an average,
这可能有点像概括或计数 可能是一个平均值
a median.
中位数
We'll go through bunch of these possibilities later.
稍后我们仔细讨论这些概率
Once you have that summary, now you have an actual complete metric definition,
总结后 你便得到了一个完整的指标定义
and now that you go into all of the other steps that Kerry talked about in
现在你需要完成 Kerry 在介绍中谈到的
the introduction.
所有其他步骤
Okay. But before we get into that,
好的 在此之前
I have one more question.
我还有一个问题
It sounds like for sanity checking, you might need multiple metrics.
比如完整性检查 你可能需要多个指标
But how about for evaluation?
那评估呢？
Should you stick to just one metric there, or do you also use multiple?
你应该坚持一个指标 还是使用多个指标？
>> It may depend culturally on the company and where you are, and
从文化角度来看 这取决于公司和你在公司是什么职位
how comfortable people are with the data.
人们对这些数据的适应性
You can certainly pick one metric and some companies do,
当然 你可以选择一个指标 一些公司的确会这么做
but at the same time, you know, your leaders may be more comfortable with
但同时 你知道 你的领导可能更愿意使用
a whole suite of metrics where they can see how things move.
一整套指标 他们可以看到事情如何发展
Now for PR purposes, external reporting, you may really have to settle on
出于公关目的 在外部报告中 你可能需要制定一个
a single overall objective that you have for the company.
公司总体目标
And certainly if you work at a large company, you have the problem that
当然 如果你在一家大公司工作 可能会遇到一个问题
you don't want to have one team working towards one goal and
你不想让一个团队朝着一个目标
another team working towards another one.
另一个团队朝着另一个目标努力
And so you may, in that case, also want to settle on a single objective.
因此 在这种情况下 你可能想设定一个目标
>> Now, one thing that you can do is if you have multiple metrics,
现在 你能做的是如果有多个指标
you can create a composite metric.
可以创建一个复合指标
This can be something called an objective function or an OEC,
称为目标函数或 OEC
which is, stands for an overall evaluation criterion,
意思是综合评估标准
which is a term that Microsoft uses for when they come up with a weighted
这是微软在加权函数的基础上
function that combines all of these different metrics.
结合所有不同的指标提出的一个术语
So when you do that, you now have a single combined metric
因此 你现在拥有一个综合指标
that summarizes all your individual metrics.
将你所有的单个指标汇总在一起
>> Now personally, I tend to shy away from composite metrics,
现在 我个人而言 倾向于避免使用复合指标
because of course, first you have to agree on a definition.
当然 首先你必须确定一个定义
And getting everyone to agree to a combination of revenue and users and
让大家认同收益和用户
all this other stuff can be very tricky.
但这个要做的事情很棘手
I mean, it's hard to define.
我的意思是 很难进行定义
The second is you can run into problems if you over-optimize,
其次 如果你过度优化 看重一件事情
looking at one thing, and you don't actually look at how other things move,
而忽略其他事情是如何发展的
particularly if you, if you make a radical change to your site.
尤其是如果你对网站进行一些重大修改 你会遇到一些问题
And then, the third is issue is just that the moment this metric
第三 开始使用这个指标时
starts to move, everyone who askz you to have a single metric typically comes and
每个人都会问你
says well, why is it moving?
为什么使用这个指标？
And you end up looking at all these different things, anyway.
最后无论如何你都要考虑所有这些不同的事情
>> Yeah, you basically go right back looking at all the individual metrics.
是的 你主要需要回头看看所有这些单独的指标
I agree with Carrie.
我同意 Carrie 的观点
Now, the last situation that you'll sort of think about when you're trying
现在 选择一个指标时你需要考虑的最后一种情况是
to choose a metric is how generally applicable the metric is.
这个指标是否普遍适用
If you're running a whole suite of AB tests, then ideally you'd have one or
如果你正在运行一整套 A/B 测试 理想情况是你的一个或多个指标
more metrics that you can use across the entire suite.
适用整套测试过程
It's much better to use a metric that's less optimal for
比起一个完美的指标
your test, if you can use it across the suites that you can do the comparison,
你最好选择一个没有那么完美
than it is to come up with the perfect metric for your test.
但是适用于整套测试 能够用来对比的指标
Whenever you do something custom, it just introduces more risk.
无论什么时候 你自定义一些内容时 会增加更多风险
>> That makes sense.
有道理
Now let's get started by coming up with some high-level concepts for metrics.
现在 我们来想一想一些指标的高级概念